{
    "id": "61c4f6cd4fa043f2b4e67ad411d6a0a2",
    "title": "Conjunctions Quiz",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I was ill .......................... I didn't go to work.",
            "description": "The conjunction 'so' shows the result whereas the conjunctions as and because show the cause.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "because",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9f64cd956c304ed19f4faf72be63fdbe"
        },
        {
            "question": "You should get your license renewed at once ................... pay a fine.",
            "description": "The conjunction 'or' is used to present alternatives.",
            "answers": [
                "or",
                "nor",
                "but"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "67fc5d852c044afcacf4fc373fb7d19f"
        },
        {
            "question": ".......................... there is no demand for this type of book, I cannot place an order.",
            "description": "The conjunctions as and since are used to give the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "Since",
                "As",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e0cf170806e440d9a31424f26765866c"
        },
        {
            "question": "My grandfather has never flown in an airplane .......................... does he want to fly in one.",
            "description": "Neither and nor can mean 'also not'. They can come at the beginning of a clause and are followed by an inverted word order.",
            "answers": [
                "neither",
                "nor",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f7fdcd45c5634cf0ad0918eae3ed9313"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am very tired ................................ I have been working all day.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "because",
                "therefore"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0e84188b7c9e4a05aaae8ac6d1fab245"
        },
        {
            "question": "She not only gave us a fine dinner ......................... drove us back home.",
            "description": "The correct expression is not only / but also.",
            "answers": [
                "but",
                "but also",
                "also"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7a8c6e3fff994e7fb87a83141181d472"
        },
        {
            "question": "Cold ............................. it was, we went out.",
            "description": "After an adjective or adverb, as and though can be used to mean 'although'. Note that although is not possible in this structure. ",
            "answers": [
                "though",
                "although",
                "even though"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f09cf2f042ba499f84950b875dd53e61"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am not angry. ............................. anything I feel a little surprised.",
            "description": "If can be used before non-assertive words like any, anything, ever and not.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Unless",
                "Whether"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3cd203ad4e1f45b788ab5f22ce028689"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Kaziranga National Park is a World Heritage Site ....................... hosts two-thirds of the one-horned rhinoceros in the world.",
            "description": "'That' is a relative pronoun but it is also possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "7655f1ddb72d4f8ab9d5ceb0b526e355"
        },
        {
            "question": "August 31st is a national holiday ............................ everybody dances in the streets.",
            "description": "When indicates time where indicates place. That cannot be used instead of when or where.",
            "answers": [
                "when",
                "where",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "27fd5b7db08e4ab1a48ad99767e34f11"
        },
        {
            "question": "Strange ............................ it may sound, I don't like watching cricket.",
            "description": "After an adjective or an adverb, as and though can be used in a special structure. ",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "though",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "7b0a25e3910d4b61a1145e4226c4bc39"
        },
        {
            "question": "We will get there ................................... you do.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "sonner",
                "as soon as",
                "as soon than"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "465f533f3db94228939f93ed97f2b9c8"
        }
    ]
}